hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft we're
going straight into the nether oh that's
making me feel sick we're going straight
into the nether for the start of this
episode oh
why hello there
i am going to decorate my nether pore
but i've just realized i haven't
actually shown you guys the nether hub
so a lot of you have probably seen this
it's been a project in the works for
quite some time now and i mean that a
quite some time now i actually didn't
actually contribute that much but one
day iskall and cub just went nuts
and they made this a miniature map of
the entire world now there isn't
actually any of the buildings or
anything or the main points but it's so
clean it's you wouldn't even guess that
you were in the nether unless you could
see like you know the red mist but
this is a nether hub you know this is
crazy
and i absolutely love the way it looks
so these are all different hermits bases
or points of interest my one
is over here in the ocean now to make
mine look more like my base i'm going to
edit this slightly and don't worry i've
already got permission for this from the
people that uh made it so we're all
gonna sort of decorate it ever so subtly
now
i need to make this three blocks
otherwise it's not gonna work but i'm
just gonna widen it a tiny bit make it
just a tiny bit bigger because my base
is really big on the server so even if
it's a little bit higher it's not a big
deal now what i learned from kerb is
that you can actually
put item frames and maps on it and it
still works as a portal so
i can place these all the way around
kind of like in the infinity room and i
can turn my entire portal into a white
color to match what my base looks like
now it's got to be like that
unfortunately that's the minimum i can
do but
hopefully this works and then i can
mimic the fact that i've got some
pillars here and i can try my best
to make it seem
like my base which is why i've made it
one block wider so that i can complete
my three pillar system of course this
isn't going to look perfect it's it's
going to look like item frames somewhat
because
the light and there's the side so you
can see so the side there it's not going
to be totally matching up but
on the whole i think this looks pretty
cool
you know what that actually looks pretty
good i'm i'm happy with that now if only
i could make that white but i can't i
tell you what i could potentially do is
i could decorate it ever so slightly
just enough to make it look a bit more
circular that way it minimizes the
obsidian
and i think that might be a little bit
too tall although my bass is really
really tall
uh if it is too big then of course i can
just scale it down but i think that's
pretty good looking from what i can see
so right if this works
there we go the portal is directly in
the middle and then i add the last map
and there we have the green base in
miniature so the problem was that i was
flying around here and i couldn't
actually work out which portal was mine
at a glance but now let's see what this
looks like you can tell i know it's a
bit out of focus but as soon as you come
into render distance you can tell that
it's mine actually yeah that's that's
kind of a negative the fact that if
you're flying over here
you just see item frames yes if you zoom
in you can see it but
i think that works quite well i'd love
to hear your opinions i could perhaps
try and fix this a bit more but it's
meant to be just a tiny representation
of my base and i think it's gone pretty
well i'm the first person to do this so
maybe people will follow my lead
i noticed that mumbo doesn't even have
one here so i don't know how he's
getting to the nether he might be using
my portal
so that's one thing off of my checklist
now i've been searching high and low
through the mess that is my base
looking for
the iscal architect lol piece of paper
i cannot find it anywhere this is a
total mess
so
i think i'm going to send him a letter
in a slightly different way
we
are going to send him a letter
in real life
yep we're going to send him a letter in
real life but it's going to be so epic
so let's crack on shall we i've already
thought this out i need to find myself
these empty maps now what i'm going to
do is i'm going to rename them so i've
renamed this check your mail now i've
got a second one there just in case he
does something that i'm expecting him to
do so we're going to go and find him and
we're going to literally drop this piece
of paper to say check your mail now
because i'm smart i've thought ahead and
i've actually written out this letter
and i've sent it ahead of time if my
timings are correct
which they're probably not the letter
should arrive
very very quickly
after i've done this and then by the
time you see this episode
no
by the time you see this
by the time you see this episode he
should have already got it so you can't
even spoil it for him
where has this phantom gone on guard
i'm gonna get this phantom midair it's
gonna be it's gonna be epic he's going
for me
yeah
i got him oh beautiful
i think phantoms are extremely annoying
but they're really really cool so now
i've just got to wait for iskall to
actually get online so i can give him
this note since we're waiting we might
as well check our shops we haven't done
that and no one's buying sand
oh okay a few people are buying sand
maybe it's too expensive
you know what let's drop the price
actually
i'm thinking that maybe i should take
all of this stock back
because
we've actually mumbo and i been starting
to think about the sahara project that i
discussed earlier i have set up two
beacons and i have been flattening this
world very very slowly this area here is
where the shop's going to be and it's
absolutely massive as you can tell i
need two beacons so the plan is to shape
this area up and get it looking
presentable before we build something
now i've actually produced a sketch of
what i think is going to go here and i
think we could do just a tiny bit of
work on it before iskal is officially
well if he accepts officially added to
the architect group and then we can go
full steam ahead on the savannah project
and a lot of people commented right
saying that i'm pretty sure amazon is
called amazon
because it's got lots of variety just
like the wildlife so i was thinking
sahara could also have lots and lots of
things but our motto is yeah but we've
also got a lot of sand
and i mean that quite literally on the
side i've been collecting sand to sell
in this project i have actually got 10
shulker boxes full of sand now that is a
lot of sand so i'm thinking maybe we can
play on that with our ethos kind of
thing
what do you sell
we sell everything but we also have a
lot of sand just like the real sahara
desert i'm thinking maybe we need to
talk to tfc because he's about to get
the biggest shop on the server plonked
right outside of his base maybe we could
offer him an upgrade on the shack
because i'm be honest with you guys
i don't think this has changed since the
start of the season maybe he would jump
at the opportunity i don't know
and just my luck iskall has come online
so let's go and see where he is
i'm guessing that he's at his base
is he there
is he is he in the giant worm
he's usually
somewhere down here
and i would know this because i love to
mess about with this whole place
hello
anybody home
okay i can confirm that he's definitely
not there so i've got to go and find him
the only other place that i think he
could be is in the shopping district i
don't know where else to find him he's
definitely online so
ah there he is oh okay so now i know
where he is he's working on the the rail
network so if i just get this
so the plan is i dive in i drop the
check your mail sign so hopefully i
could do this on the sly
there he is if he's flying oh watch this
this is gonna be great i'm gonna i'm
gonna rock up
he just totally saw it was me but i just
i did do an airdrop he should see that
it says check your mail okay now my
first thought is that he's gonna think
in game this building here the mail room
which i don't think i've actually ever
seen so if i go straight over to iskals
and then i put no your real life mail
here's mine and you've been jingled uh
it's just loads of yeah it's just loads
of selling stuff okay so hopefully
iskall will
wrongly interpret this as the
hermitcraft mail and then head straight
on over there now i kind of want to see
this
so
hopefully he gets the note the real
question is why didn't i just say this
in chat the answer is because it's more
fun this way
it's more fun to hand deliver notes you
know i hope that i hope that no there is
there is i knew it i knew it so he's
gone straight to the mail room
so you're probably wondering what's
going on here right because this is all
a bit strange why am i going through all
of this and the answer is i am sending
him the letter in real life as you know
but what i haven't told you is this
isn't an ordinary letter i've really
gone over the top so
i'm going to cut into real life now
and show you the process that i went
through to make this extremely special
here we go
[Music]
do
so if my calculations are correct iskow
should now have received the letter
because i should have timed this fairly
well and later on i'm hoping that iskall
will then log back on later and let us
know that he's joining architects but
maybe he won't maybe maybe he won't join
us who knows either way we need to get
started on the sahara project big time
there's a lot to do and i've already
started obviously and i'm actually going
to have to move this rail network i've
already spoken to ren i'm going to move
this underground because it's right
where most of the building's going to go
so this is going to be underground with
a glass uh ceiling above it
and i think we should probably move on
to a quick time lapse of us cleaning
this area up and preparing it for the
build to come so since we're here doing
a time lapse i thought i would talk
about the letter time lapse thing that
you just saw and how much effort went
into it okay so
that wasn't just some random letter that
i wrote i didn't actually write it
myself i actually got a calligrapher
which is basically a professional writer
to do some fancy pants writing on some
stained paper
and i also ordered a custom wax seal so
it has the a t which obviously stands
for architects to make it seem all
proper and official and i went through a
lot of effort to make this letter look
absolutely phenomenal and i think it
came out well i cannot wait to see
iskall's response and guess who
didn't press f1 for yet another time
lapse that's me on the screen you can
see that i've basically just taken the
three levels and i've flattened them out
and tried to
basically make this area prepared for
the giant build that's going to go here
so
along with mumbo and hopefully iskall
we will be able to start building this
gigantic project now that everything is
laid out properly all right let's get
back into game and it's looking pretty
clean now
so that's pretty much where i want to
leave the sahara project for now until
at least we can consult mumbo and iskal
because i can do this bit by myself
that's not a problem but when it comes
to the final design and actually putting
down the blocks i think all three of us
have to do this
but there's now another project that i
want to work on for the rest of this
episode and it's a little strange to say
the least
so a couple of episodes ago
a
salmon figure appeared on well there's a
couple right there
a
the salmon ghost is that did i just get
one
that that that that's the thing
i can't believe it yeah this is it it's
totally a salmon head so basically one
of these appeared very briefly maybe
i'll show a clip of it right here you
can see it on the right and it freaked
me out it dropped a pickle and then it
ran away
it's so yeah it's a
look look at this
look at this look at this
he looks so emotionally dead
so i'm pretty sure this is what i saw
everyone's been calling him the salmon
ghost
whatever it might be
this thing appeared in my video and
nobody knows what it is since then it's
been seen in other videos
so ren said that he's also seen it and
quite clearly someone is messing with us
and essentially i want to get to the
bottom of this mystery
and there's no way that i can just you
know investigate this as myself i think
we're going to have to become a proper
detective
so i'm going to open a shop well more
like
a building
that looks awfully familiar to those
that like detective stories so i'm
thinking i'm going to make it right here
and create a bridge over
and we're going to become sherlock green
so i think the first thing that we got
to do is shave off all of this so this
is a good place to have the side of it
and the i'm basically going to google
pictures of 221b
baker street which for those of you that
don't know
is the home of sure the fictional home
rather it's not real but the fictional
home of sherlock holmes
so
let's get cracking on it
this may also be a really good way for
me to make a few diamonds you know
solving mysteries perhaps i can get to
the bottom of who the jingler is
although the jingler's not really done
anything for a long time so maybe that's
a bit pointless but hopefully
i can get a few clients in to pay me
some money to solve some mysteries or
something
i'm a smart cookie i can i can figure
this out
now the reason that i'm putting this
building into the side of a mountain is
because i'm a little bit lazy to be
honest with you i can just build the
front of it and i don't have to worry
about the rest of the building
this might not be tall enough but i'm
sure it's not a big deal if it overlaps
just a tiny tiny bit so let's kick this
off with a bass so this is bringing me
back vibes from my video where i made
like how to make
an old-fashioned city you know like a
city style stuff with terraced houses
which is very much why i want it in a
cliff edge so i don't have to make the
back of it
this actually may end up being very very
tall so i might want to thin this up a
little bit now i'm going to use the
smooth sandstone because i feel like
this will work best if you look up these
london houses the picture that i'm using
as a reference for 221b baker street it
has sort of like the yellow
sandstone bottom and hopefully this will
match up it's a bit little bit brighter
than perhaps i would like but
it should work all the same i'm gonna
add in any windows and stuff afterwards
another thing that i wanted to mention
actually in regards to the letter that
i've made for iskal
it he actually doesn't know anything
about it it might be very easy to just
assume that i told him about it he had
no idea that i was
planning this at all i actually got his
address which i didn't know from rendog
who has actually visited him in the past
i had to do this so sneakily i have
noticed that this is actually going to
be
a lot taller than i thought
now i actually made it slightly over to
the right here
because
that is where i believe the sahara
project is all going to go so it's going
to be right next to it anyway
but unfortunately i think the shop is
going to go right up so it might
actually be really funny because i think
duke the dog over there is going to be
peering over the top of it
and it could look really funny but i
honest i also don't really want to cover
it up but i i'm not sure what else to do
because
i really think it's going to end up
being about that tall
maybe i should move it or maybe i should
continue with it because juke the dog's
not going anywhere and the same with the
mumbo statue
there's not a shop there really but it
does seem a shame to cover it up so let
me know if i should move it because i
don't think i can actually continue this
build any further than this so i've got
like the bottom half started and getting
there there's obviously no window yet
there's no lighting no details etc etc
but you get the scale that i'm trying to
go for the reason i can't actually
continue
is because i have no bricks i'm going to
make the top half out of bricks it's
going to be very very reminiscent of
downtown evo from that series
because it's basically built in the same
style but i can't continue for now so if
i'm going to move it now's a pretty good
time but it's also a little bit too late
hey duke the dog if you're out there
watching can you let me know if it's
okay or send me an email
it's your permission that i need really
anyway i think that that is all that i
have time for today my goodness did we
get a lot done it has been very very
productive we have started on
221b baker street which is going to be
sherlock green's new home because
there's a weird salmon
skulking around
we have done some work over here to the
future sahara project and iskgao
actually i forgot to tell you iskall
here's a little bit of footage of it i
wasn't actually like recording at the
time but i i just hit record basically
he said i accept and i replied saying
okay lol
so iskall is officially in architect
group and we can get started on this
project there are big things coming many
mysteries to unravel
and of course many more projects to be
built on so that's it for me everyone
big big thank you for watching as always
and i'll see you in the next video good
bye